<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>204</law_id><section_number>8-2068</section_number><catch_line>DEDICATION OF SYSTEMS.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2068</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2068/</url><token>8-2068</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="B">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="577" prefix=""><text>Before any person, firm or corporation shall connect in any manner any privately owned water or sewer line or lines or system with any water or sewer line or lines of the City, including water or sewer lines dedicated to the City, such person, firm or corporation shall, by proper written instrument, in consideration of making such connection and the benefits to be derived therefrom, dedicate, give, grant and convey such water, or sewer line, or lines or system to the City; no such connection shall be made with the City water or sewer line or lines without the express approval of the City, nor shall such connection be effected except by the forces or employees of the City properly supervised, for which a charge may be made; and should any person, firm or corporation connect any privately owned water or sewer line or lines or system with any City water or sewer line or lines without first dedicating, giving, granting and conveying same to the City the act of connecting such water or sewer line or lines to the water or sewer line or lines of the City shall be deemed a dedication, gift, grant and conveyance of such water or sewer line or lines to the City. 
(Ord. No. 1985-543, &#xA7;25, 4-16-85) 
Charter reference: Authority to require dedication, &#xA7;2.14(65).</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section/></prefixes><entire_prefix/><prefix_anchor/><level>1</level></section></text></law>
