<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>209</law_id><section_number>8-2073</section_number><catch_line>DISCONTINUANCE OF SERVICE BY CITY.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2073</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2073/</url><token>8-2073</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="B">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="582" prefix=""><text>The City shall have the right to cut off the water and to discontinue the furnishing of water and sewer services through the utility lines constructed and dedicated pursuant to this article, at any time, without notice, whenever it shall appear to the City in the sole and absolute discretion of the governing body of the City that to continue to furnish water or sewer services to the consumers along any of the lines would render the City unable to properly furnish an adequate water supply or adequate sewer service for the use of its consumers and citizens living within the corporate limits of the City, but in such event, the City shall give the dedicators and the consumers an ample notice of such intention to discontinue the water supply or sewer service, or both, as the circumstances of the situation render practicable. The City specifically does not and shall not agree or undertake or be required to furnish to the dedicators or to any consumer along any of the utility lines constructed and dedicated pursuant to this article and the Charter any stated or particular pressure of water, and the City specifically does not and shall not agree to furnish fire protection, nor shall there be any such responsibility. The City shall not be liable to the dedicators or to any consumer or to any person for any failure to supply water or for the character or quality of the water supplied, or for any failure or inadequacy of sewer service. 
(Code 1959 , &#xA7;23-24) 
State law reference: Discontinuance of service for nonpayment, G.S. 160A-214.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section/></prefixes><entire_prefix/><prefix_anchor/><level>1</level></section></text></law>
