<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>189</law_id><section_number>8-2038</section_number><catch_line>DEPTH AT WHICH SEWER LINES TO BE LAID; CITY INSTALLATIONS.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2038</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2038/</url><token>8-2038</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="B">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="559" prefix=""><text>The City shall not be obligated to install facilities to provide gravity sewer service to any floor level of any existing or proposed structure at an elevation lower than ten (10) feet below the crown of the street directly in front of the structure. Notwithstanding this provision, property owners desiring that the line be placed at a depth greater than necessary to serve a floor level ten (10) feet below the crown of the street shall be required to pay the difference in cost of laying such line at that depth and the depth at which the property owner desires the line to be laid. Such cost shall be estimated by the City based on the difference in cost for installing a line at twelve (12) feet of depth and the depth at which the property owner desires the line to be laid. Payment of the estimated cost shall be made within thirty (30) days of the date of the demand for payment or the line will be laid at a depth as if the property owner had not requested that the line be installed at a greater depth. Notwithstanding the payment of the estimated cost of the greater depth of lines, the property owner making the payment shall still be assessed for his proportionate cost of the installation of the line consistent with the normal assessment policy. 
(Res. No. 1963-948, &#xA7;1, 5-6-63; Ord. No. 1983-63, &#xA7;1, 2-1-83; Ord. No. 1985-543, &#xA7;4, 4-16-85)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section/></prefixes><entire_prefix/><prefix_anchor/><level>1</level></section></text></law>
