<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>201</law_id><section_number>8-2066</section_number><catch_line>EASEMENT AND RIGHTS-OF-WAY, PROCURING.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2066</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2066/</url><token>8-2066</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="B">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="574" prefix=""><text>In the event that the utility lines are to be constructed and laid in and along any public highway or the right-of-way thereof, or in and across lands not owned and possessed by the promoters or developers or in and across lands owned and possessed by the developers or promoters but not within the current phase of development, the promoters and developers without cost or expense to the City shall procure the necessary and proper written easement or right-of-way deeds from the proper officials and agencies having control of such public highways and from the owners of such lands granting the right and authority to construct, improve, install, remove, replace, maintain, inspect and repair and use such utility lines, together with all appurtenant facilities and equipment necessary and convenient thereto, with appropriate rights of ingress and egress over private lands, when necessary, with the right to remove and keep removed therefrom all trees, shrubs, underbrush or parts thereof and other obstructions as necessary to maintain, repair, or protect the utility system. The City will join in the execution of such documents, when required, subject to approval of the legal instrument by the City Attorney. 
(Ord. No. 1985-543, &#xA7;25, 4-16-85) 
Cross references: City Attorney, &#xA7;1-1021 et seq.; technical provisions concerning plumbing requirements on making utility connections, &#xA7;10-6071 et seq. 
State law reference: Permits required for work in state roads, G.S. 136-93.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section/></prefixes><entire_prefix/><prefix_anchor/><level>1</level></section></text></law>
