<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>308</law_id><section_number>8-2176</section_number><catch_line>VOLUNTARY WATER USE MEASURES.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2176</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2176/</url><token>8-2176</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="E">ARTICLE E. - WATER CONSERVATION PLAN [6]</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="939" prefix="(a)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="940" prefix="(b)"><text>Indoor Water Uses: 
1.	Thaw frozen food in your refrigerator or microwave instead of using running water. Wash fruits and vegetables with a vegetable brush in a basin or bowl instead of using running water. 
2.	Scrape or wipe, rather than rinse, dishes before loading into the dishwasher. Wash only full loads. Consider replacing old dishwasher with a water and energy saving model. 
3.	Wash only full loads of laundry or use the appropriate water level or load size selection on the washing machine. Presoak heavily soiled items. Use detergent sparingly in order to avoid rinsing more than normal cycle. Consider purchasing a high efficiency washing machine to save laundry water and energy. 
4.	Install low-flow toilets, faucet aerators, and low-flow showerheads.
5.	Leaky toilet can waste two hundred (200) gallons of water per day. To detect leaks in a toilet, add a few drops of food coloring to the tank water. Do not flush. Wait a few minutes. The toilet is leaking if the colored water appears in the bowl. 
6.	Commercial and industrial customers not otherwise regulated as a major water user should review their water uses and should consider implementing industry specific best management water conservation practices. 
7.	Check for leaks in toilets, faucets, shower heads and any other plumbing fixtures and repair these leaks immediately.
(Ord. No. 2007-235, &#xA7;1, 5-15-07; Ord. No. 2010-793, &#xA7;4, 10-19-10; Ord. No. 2012-48, &#xA7;2, 5-14-12)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text></law>
