<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>253</law_id><section_number>8-2136</section_number><catch_line>DISCHARGE OF HAZARDOUS WASTE BY INDUSTRIAL USERS.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2136</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2136/</url><token>8-2136</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="C">ARTICLE C. - USE OF SANITARY SEWER SYSTEM [4]</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="792" prefix="(a)"><text>Any user who commences the discharge of hazardous waste shall notify the POTW, the EPA Regional Waste Management Division Director, and State hazardous waste authorities, in writing, of any discharge into the POTW of a substance which, if otherwise disposed of, would be a hazardous waste under 40 CFR Part 261. Such notification must include the name of the hazardous waste as set forth in 40 CFR Part 261, the EPA hazardous waste number, and the type of discharge (continuous, batch, or other). If the user discharges more than one hundred (100) kilograms of such waste per calendar month to the POTW, the notification also shall contain the following information to the extent such information is known and readily available to the user: an identification of the hazardous constituents contained in the wastes, an estimation of the mass and concentration of such constituents in the waste stream discharge during the calendar month, and an estimation of the mass and concentration of such constituents in the waste stream expected to be discharged during the following twelve (12) months. All notifications must take place no later than one hundred and eighty (180) days before the discharge commences. The user shall not begin the discharge until receipt of written approval from the City. Any notification under this paragraph need be submitted only once for each hazardous waste discharge. However, notifications of changed conditions must be submitted under &#xA7;8-2132 of this article. The notification requirement in this section does not apply to pollutants already reported by users subject to categorical pretreatment standards under the self-monitoring requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7;8-2128, 8-2130, and 8-2131 of this article.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="793" prefix="(b)"><text>Dischargers are exempt from the requirements of subsection (a) above during a calendar month in which they discharge no more than fifteen (15) kilograms of hazardous wastes, unless the wastes are acute hazardous wastes as specific in 40 CFR 261.30(d) and 261.33(e). Discharge of more than fifteen (15) kilograms of non-acute hazardous wastes in a calendar month, or of any quantity of acute hazardous wastes as specified in 40 CFR 261.30(d) and 261.33(e), requires a one-time notification. Subsequent months during which the user discharges more than such quantities of any hazardous waste do not require additional notification.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="794" prefix="(c)"><text>In the case of any new regulation under Section 3001 of RCRA identifying additional characteristics of hazardous waste or listing any additional substance as a hazardous waste, the user must notify the POTW Director, the EPA Regional Waste Management Waste Division Director, and state hazardous waste authorities of the discharge of such substance within ninety (90) days of the effective date of such regulations.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="795" prefix="(d)"><text>In the case of any notification made under this section, the user shall certify that it has a program in place to reduce the volume and toxicity of hazardous wastes generated to the degree it has determined to be economically practical.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(d)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(d)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(d)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="796" prefix="(e)"><text>This provision does not create a right to discharge any substance not otherwise permitted to be discharged by this article, a permit issued there under, or any applicable Federal or state law. 
(Ord. No. 2011-981, &#xA7;1, 12-6-11)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(e)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(e)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(e)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text></law>
