<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>282</law_id><section_number>8-2149</section_number><catch_line>INSTALLATION OF CONTAINMENT DEVICES.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2149</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2149/</url><token>8-2149</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="D">ARTICLE D. - WATER QUALITY PROTECTION [5]</unit></structure><referred_to_by><reference>8-2148</reference></referred_to_by><text><section id="880" prefix="(a)"><text>The containment devices shall be located off street right-of-way on the water main side of any plumbing connections. When installed in a building, the device shall be located on the service line immediately after its entrance into the building. Each containment and confinement device shall be installed in a location which is physically accessible for inspection and testing as determined by the cross connection coordinator. Containment devices which have been buried in the ground do not satisfy the provisions of this Code. Each reduced pressure principal zone device is unlikely as determined by the cross connection coordinator.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="881" prefix="(b)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="882" prefix="(c)"><text>In those cases in which containment and/or confinement devices have been previously installed by prior owners, the City, or other parties, the responsibility for maintenance, testing, and replacement as applicable shall be with the consumer.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="883" prefix="(d)"><text>The cost of said means of containment, and any other plumbing modifications necessary and convenient thereto, and the testing and maintenance thereof, is to be paid for by the consumer. 
(Ord. No. 1987-20, &#xA7;1, 7-21-87)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(d)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(d)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(d)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text></law>
