<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>288</law_id><section_number>8-2155</section_number><catch_line>ENFORCEMENT BY CIVIL PENALTY.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2155</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2155/</url><token>8-2155</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="D">ARTICLE D. - WATER QUALITY PROTECTION [5]</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="895" prefix="(a)"><text>Penalty. 
Violation of any provision of this article may subject the offender to a civil penalty to be recovered by the City in a civil action in the nature of debt if the offender does not pay the penalty within thirty (30) days after the assessment has become final by exhaustion of the appeal process established by this section, or by failure to appeal the assessment. 
The civil penalty for violation of any provision of this cross connection control article shall not exceed five hundred dollars ($500.00) per day for each day of continuous violation, or a cumulative or single civil penalty of ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00). The civil penalty for willful violation of any provision of this article shall not exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) per day for each day of a continuous violation, or a cumulative or single civil penalty of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00).</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="896" prefix="(b)"><text>Assessment. 
Any civil penalty shall be assessed by the City Manager, upon the recommendation of the Director of Public Utilities, and shall be based upon the reasonable estimated cost of correcting the cited violation, the magnitude of the potential risk posed to the public health, safety and welfare by the violation, and the cost of the public safety or other emergency response caused by the violation. The City Manager shall serve written notice of the civil penalty assessment on the offender and set out with reasonable care the basis of the amount so assessed.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="897" prefix="(c)"><text>Equitable relief. 
The provisions of this article may be endorsed by an appropriate equitable remedy, including a mandatory or prohibitory injunction, issuing from a court of competent jurisdiction.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="898" prefix="(d)"><text>Enforcement option. 
The penalties and enforcement provisions established by this article may be applied in addition to or in lieu of the penalties established by other sections of this Code. 
(Ord. No. 1987-20, &#xA7;1, 7-21-87)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(d)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(d)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(d)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text></law>
