<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>223</law_id><section_number>8-2111</section_number><catch_line>PURPOSE AND POLICY.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2111</order_by><text><section id="618" prefix="(a)"><text>This article sets forth uniform requirements for direct and indirect contributors into the waste water collection and treatment system for the City of Raleigh, hereafter referred to as the City, and enables the City to comply with all applicable state and Federal laws, Federal regulations and state rules including 15A NCAC 02H Part .0900, the Clean Water Act (33 United States Code Section 1251 et seq.) and the General Pretreatment Regulations (40 CFR, Part 403).</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="619" prefix="(b)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="620" prefix="(1)"><text>	To prevent the introduction of pollutants into the municipal waste water system which will interfere with the operation of the system or contaminate the resulting sludge; 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(1)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(1)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(1)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="621" prefix="(2)"><text>	To prevent the introduction of pollutants into the municipal waste water system which will pass through the system, inadequately treated, into any waters of the State or otherwise be incompatible with the system; 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(2)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(2)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(2)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="622" prefix="(3)"><text>	To promote reuse and recycling of industrial waste water and sludges from the municipal system; 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(3)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(3)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(3)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="623" prefix="(4)"><text>	To protect both municipal personnel who may be affected by sewage, sludge, and effluent in the course of their employment as well as protecting the general public; 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(4)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(4)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(4)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="624" prefix="(5)"><text>	To provide for equitable distribution of the cost of operation, maintenance and improvement of the municipal waste water system; and 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(5)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(5)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(5)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="625" prefix="(6)"><text>	To ensure that the municipality complies with its NPDES or Non-discharge Permit conditions, sludge use and disposal requirements, and any other Federal or state laws to which the municipal waste water system is subject. 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(6)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(6)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(6)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="626" prefix="(c)"><text>This article provides for the regulation of direct and indirect contributors to the municipal waste water system, through the issuance of permits to certain non-domestic users and through enforcement of general requirements for the other users, authorizes monitoring and enforcement activities, requires user reporting, and provides for the setting of fees for the equitable distribution of costs resulting from the program established herein.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="627" prefix="(d)"><text>This article shall apply to all users of the municipal waste water system. [Note: as authorized by G.S. 160A-312 and/or G.S. 153A-275.] Except as otherwise provided herein, the POTW Director shall administer, implement, and enforce the provisions of this article. Any powers granted to or imposed upon the POTW Director may be delegated by the POTW Director to other City personnel. By discharging waste water into the municipal waste water system, industrial users located within or outside the City limits agree to comply with the terms and conditions established in this article, as well as any permits, enforcement actions, or orders issued hereunder. 
(Ord. No. 2011-981, &#xA7;1, 12-6-11)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(d)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(d)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(d)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text><metadata/><url>/8-2111/</url><token>8-2111</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="C">ARTICLE C. - USE OF SANITARY SEWER SYSTEM [4]</unit></structure><referred_to_by><reference>8-2117</reference></referred_to_by></law>
