<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>287</law_id><section_number>8-2154</section_number><catch_line>TESTING AND MAINTENANCE OF DEVICES.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2154</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2154/</url><token>8-2154</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="D">ARTICLE D. - WATER QUALITY PROTECTION [5]</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="894" prefix=""><text>The consumer at each property at which containment and/or confinement device(s) have been installed, except those with devices installed in accordance with &#xA7;8-2148(a) of this Code, shall have each containment and/or confinement device(s) tested on an annual basis, and perform any routine maintenance to such device as recommended by the manufacturer, and provide the cross connection coordinator with a report of that inspection and work. Backflow prevention devices that require testing must be done so with equipment approved by the City of Raleigh. The consumer shall cause such maintenance or repairs to be made, rendering the device fully operational. Failure of the consumer to perform that testing and maintenance shall be cause for the premises to be deemed an immediate public health hazard. The Director of Public Utilities may immediately thereafter discontinue public water supply service to that premises and service shall not be restored until such devices have been rendered fully operational. Where the use of water is critical to the continuance of normal operations or protection of life, property, or equipment, duplicate containment or confinement devices shall be provided by the property owner to avoid the necessity of discontinuing water service to test or repair the device or devices. 
(Ord. No. 1987-20, &#xA7;1, 7-21-87; Ord. No. 1992-3, &#xA7;6, 7-7-92)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section/></prefixes><entire_prefix/><prefix_anchor/><level>1</level></section></text></law>
