<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>243</law_id><section_number>8-2128</section_number><catch_line>BASELINE MONITORING REPORTS.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2128</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2128/</url><token>8-2128</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="C">ARTICLE C. - USE OF SANITARY SEWER SYSTEM [4]</unit></structure><referred_to_by><reference>8-2130</reference><reference>8-2136</reference></referred_to_by><text><section id="764" prefix="(a)"><text>Within either one hundred eighty (180) days after the effective date of a categorical pretreatment standard, or the final administrative decision on a category determination under 40 CFR 403.6(a)(4), whichever is later, existing categorical users currently discharging to or scheduled to discharge to the POTW shall submit to the POTW Director a report which contains the information listed in subsection (b) below. At least ninety (90) days prior to commencement of their discharge, new sources, and sources that become categorical users subsequent to the promulgation of an applicable categorical standard, shall submit to the POTW Director a report which contains the information listed in subsection (b) below. A new source shall report the method of pretreatment it intends to use to meet applicable categorical standards. A new source also shall give estimates of its anticipated flow and quantity of pollutants to be discharged.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="765" prefix="(b)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="766" prefix="(1)"><text>	Identifying information. 
The name and address of the facility, including the name of the operator and owner. 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(1)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(1)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(1)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="767" prefix="(2)"><text>	Environmental permits. 
A list of any environmental control permits held by or for the facility. 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(2)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(2)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(2)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="768" prefix="(3)"><text>	Description of operations. 
A brief description of the nature, average rate of production, and standard industrial classifications of the operation(s) carried out by such user. This description should include a schematic process diagram which indicates points of discharge to the POTW from the regulated processes. 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(3)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(3)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(3)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="769" prefix="(4)"><text>	Flow measurement. 
Information showing the measured average daily and maximum daily flow, in gallons per day, to the POTW from regulated process streams and other streams, as necessary, to allow use of the combined waste stream formula set out in 40 CFR 403.6(e). 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(4)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(4)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(4)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="770" prefix="(5)"><text>	Measurement of pollutants. 
a.	The categorical pretreatment standards applicable to each regulated process. 
b.	The results of sampling and analysis identifying the nature and concentration, and/or mass, where required by the standard or by the POTW Director, of regulated pollutants in the discharge from each regulated process. Instantaneous, daily maximum, and long-term average concentrations, or mass, where required, shall be reported. The sample shall be representative of daily operations and shall be analyzed in accordance with procedures set out in &#xA7;8-2137 of this article. 
c.	Sampling must be performed in accordance with procedures set out in &#xA7;8-2138 of this article and 40 CFR 403.12(b) and (g), including 40 CFR 403.12(g)(4). 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(5)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(5)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(5)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="771" prefix="(6)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(6)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(6)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(6)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="772" prefix="(7)"><text>	Compliance schedule. 
If additional pretreatment and/or O &amp; M will be required to meet the pretreatment standards, the shortest schedule by which the user will provide such additional pretreatment and/or O &amp; M. The completion date in this schedule shall not be later than the compliance date established for the applicable pretreatment standard. A compliance schedule pursuant to this section must meet the requirements set out in &#xA7;8-2129 of this article. 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(7)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(7)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(7)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="773" prefix="(8)"><text>	Signature and certification. 
All baseline monitoring reports must be signed and certified in accordance with &#xA7;8-2127(3) of this article. 
(Ord. No. 2011-981, &#xA7;1, 12-6-11) 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section><section>(8)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)(8)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)(8)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section></text></law>
