<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>309</law_id><section_number>8-2177</section_number><catch_line>ENFORCEMENT.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2177</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2177/</url><token>8-2177</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="E">ARTICLE E. - WATER CONSERVATION PLAN [6]</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="941" prefix="(a)"><text>Penalty. 
Violation of any provision of this article may subject the offender to a civil penalty to be recovered by the City in a civil action in the nature of debt if the offender does not pay the penalty within thirty (30) days after the assessment has become final by exhaustion of the appeal process established by this section, or by failure to appeal the assessment and will be subject to temporary water service interruption. 
Except as otherwise provided in this article and in mandatory water use restriction ordinances, the civil penalty for violation of any provision of this article shall not exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) per day for each day of continuous violation, or a cumulative or single civil penalty of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00). The civil penalty for willful violation of any provision of this article shall not exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) per day for each day of a continuous violation, or a cumulative or single civil penalty of twenty five thousand dollars ($25,000.00).</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="942" prefix="(b)"><text>Assessment. 
Any civil penalty shall be assessed by the Public Utilities Director, and shall be based upon the reasonable estimated cost of correcting the cited violation, the magnitude of the potential risk posed to the public health, safety and welfare by the violation, and the cost of the public safety or other emergency response caused by the violation. The Public Utilities Director shall serve written notice of the civil penalty assessment on the offender and set out with reasonable care the basis of the amount so assessed.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="943" prefix="(c)"><text>Equitable relief. 
The provisions of this article may be enforced by an appropriate equitable remedy, including a mandatory or prohibitory injunction, issuing from a court of competent jurisdiction.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="944" prefix="(d)"><text>Enforcement option. 
The penalties and enforcement provisions established by this article may be applied in addition to or in lieu of the penalties established by other sections of this Code and applicable ordinances. 
(Ord. No. 2007-235, &#xA7;1, 5-15-07)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(d)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(d)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(d)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text></law>
