<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>348</law_id><section_number>8-2241</section_number><catch_line>EMERGENCY DISCONTINUATION OF SERVICE AND REPAIRS.</catch_line><history/><order_by>8-2241</order_by><metadata/><url>/8-2241/</url><token>8-2241</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="8">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="2">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="F">ARTICLE F. - REUSE WATER REGULATION [7]</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="1024" prefix=""><text>The responsibility for maintaining and repairing reuse water service stubs shall be in accord with City Code, &#xA7;10-6082. The repair of all pipes and fixtures on private property shall be the responsibility of the property owner or consumer. When a minor failure occurs in a pipe or fixture on private property, and such failure is not corrected within twelve (12) hours of notification by the Public Utilities Director to the owner or person in charge, the City, for the purpose of conserving reuse water and protecting the public, may discontinue service until the failure is corrected or enter the property and make the necessary repairs. When a major failure occurs in a line or fixture and creates the possibility of an immediate danger to the public health or safety, the City may make the necessary repairs. The work done by the City shall be limited to the necessary line repair and such backfilling as needed to protect the pipe. The cost of any repairs performed by the City shall be charged to the property owner and included in his next regular periodic reuse water bill. Failure to pay the repair bill shall be considered as a regular reuse water bill delinquency and service may be discontinued until such amount is paid. 
(Ord. No. 2006-100, &#xA7;1, 9-19-06)</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section/></prefixes><entire_prefix/><prefix_anchor/><level>1</level></section></text></law>
