<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>1004</law_id><section_number>I-IV-4.2</section_number><catch_line>RECALL OF OFFICIALS BY THE PEOPLE.</catch_line><history/><order_by>4.2</order_by><metadata/><url>/I-IV-4.2/</url><token>I-IV-4.2</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="I">Division I - Charter</unit><unit label="article" level="2" identifier="IV">ARTICLE IV. - ELECTIONS [2]</unit></structure><referred_to_by/><text><section id="4837" prefix="(1)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(1)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(1)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(1)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="4838" prefix="(2)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(2)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(2)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(2)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="4839" prefix="(3)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(3)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(3)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(3)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="4840" prefix="(4)"><text>The Wake County Board of Elections shall make, or cause to be made, publication for ten days of notice and all arrangements for holding such election, and the same shall be conducted, returned, and the results thereof declared in all respects as other City elections in the City of Raleigh. The successor of any officer so removed shall hold office during the unexpired term of his predecessor. Any person sought to be removed may be a candidate to succeed himself, and unless he requests otherwise in writing, his name shall be placed on the official ballot without nomination. At such election, if some other person than the incumbent is elected, the incumbent shall thereupon be deemed removed from the office upon qualification of his successor.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(4)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(4)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(4)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="4841" prefix="(5)"><text>In case the person elected should fail to qualify within ten days after receiving notification of election, the office shall be filled by election by the City Council, but the officer or councilor removed shall not be eligible to election by the City Council, and the person so elected by the City Council shall be subject to recall as other officers and councilors. If the incumbent received a majority of votes in the primary or the election, he shall continue in office. The said method of removal shall be cumulative and additional to any other method provided by law. The expense of calling and conducting any such election shall be paid by the City of Raleigh. 
(S.L. 1953, Ch. 347, Art. 2; S.L. 1973, Ch. 319, &#xA7;1(1))</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(5)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(5)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(5)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text></law>
