<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law><law_id>97</law_id><section_number>II-5-3001</section_number><catch_line>DEFINITIONS.</catch_line><history/><order_by>5-3001</order_by><text><section id="203" prefix="(a)"><text>Compliance; Responsibility for Enforcement. 
Compliance with the provisions of this article, including all requirements of the Fire Prevention Code adopted hereunder, shall be enforced by the inspectors of the Fire Prevention Bureau of the Fire Department. In exercising its enforcement responsibilities, the goal of the Fire Prevention Bureau shall be to employ the enforcement alternatives calculated most effectively to secure compliance with the Fire Prevention Code and other fire prevention standards and requirements of the City.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(a)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(a)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(a)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="204" prefix="(b)"><text>Violations. 
Any person, who shall violate or fail to comply with any of the provisions of this article, including the Fire Prevention Code adopted hereunder, or who shall violate or fail to comply with any corrective order of the Fire Prevention Bureau issued hereunder, or who shall build in violation of any specifications or plans submitted and approved hereunder shall be deemed to have committed a violation of this article and shall be held responsible and subject to the penalties and remedies herein provided. In addition, any such person owning, leasing, using, managing, or occupying any building, structure, or land wherein or whereon there exists anything in violation of this article, including the Fire Prevention Code, or any lawful order issued or plan approved hereunder; or any architect, builder, contractor, engineer, agent, or other person who acts in concert, participates, directs, or assists in the creation or maintenance of a violation of this article or any order issued or plan approved hereunder; or any person who shall erect or use any land, building or structure or any part thereof contrary to this article, the Fire Prevention Code, any order issued or plan approved hereunder; or any person who shall omit, neglect, or refuse to do any act provided for in this article, including the Fire Prevention Code, or any order issued or plan approved hereunder shall be held responsible for a violation of this article and be subject to the penalties and remedies herein provided.</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(b)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(b)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(b)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="205" prefix="(c)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="206" prefix="(1)"><text>	Equitable remedies, including injunctions and orders of abatement. 
As authorized by the City Council, the City may apply for any appropriate equitable remedy to enforce the provisions of this article, including mandatory or prohibitory injunctions commanding the defendant, or in the case of counterclaims the plaintiff, to correct the unlawful condition or cease the unlawful use of property; or apply for orders of abatement directing that buildings or other structures on the property be closed, demolished, or removed; that fixtures, furniture, or other movable property be moved; that improvements or repairs be made; or that other action be taken as necessary to secure compliance with the provisions of this article. 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section><section>(1)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)(1)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)(1)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="207" prefix="(2)"><text>	Criminal offense. 
A violation of this article shall constitute a misdemeanor offense as provided by G.S. 14-4; and the maximum fine or term of imprisonment, or both, as authorized by law is hereby imposed. 
</text><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section><section>(2)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)(2)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)(2)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="208" prefix="(3)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(c)</section><section>(3)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(c)(3)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(c)(3)</prefix_anchor><level>2</level></section><section id="209" prefix="(i)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(i)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(i)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(i)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section><section id="210" prefix="(d)"><text/><type>section</type><prefixes><section>(d)</section></prefixes><entire_prefix>(d)</entire_prefix><prefix_anchor>(d)</prefix_anchor><level>1</level></section></text><metadata/><url>/II-5-3001/</url><token>II-5-3001</token><structure><unit label="division" level="1" identifier="II">Division II - Planning and Development</unit><unit label="part" level="3" identifier="5">PART 5 - PUBLIC SAFETY</unit><unit label="chapter" level="4" identifier="3">CHAPTER 3. - POLICEMEN AND FIREMEN SPECIAL RELIEF FUND</unit><unit label="section" level="5" identifier="5-3001">Sec. 5-3001. - DEFINITIONS.</unit></structure><referred_to_by/></law>
